Finding Aid for School of Nursing (University of Michigan) records, 1891-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Dean Carolyne K. Davis and Successors, 1968-1980
  - Topical Files, 1968-1980
    - Health Sciences, Division of
      - 1973, 2 folders (Box 28)
      - 1974 (Box 28)
    - Institute for the Study of Mental Retardation and Related Disabilities, 1974-1980 (Box 28)
    - Male Recruitment, 1972 (Box 28)
    - Maternal-Child Health Nursing, 1976 (Box 28)
    - Michigan Board of Nursing, Progress Report, 1973 (Box 28)
    - Minority Affairs, Office of
      - Annual Reports, 1973-1976 (Box 28)
      - General, 1971-1978 (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous, 1978-1980; 2 folders (Box 28)
    - National League of Nursing (NLN)
      - Accreditation
        - Progress Report, September 1973 (Box 28)
        - Progress Report Supplement, 1973 (Box 28)
        - Report and Survey, 1977 (Box 28)
    - Nurse Clinician Program, 1977 (Box 29)
    - Nurses for Action, 1979 (Box 29)
    - Nursing Health Services Administration, 1977/78 (Box 29)
    - Nursing Research Symposium, 1974-1975 (Box 29)
    - Patient Care Crisis at University Hospital (Box 29)
    - Program Evaluation, 1976 (Box 29)
    - Reports (Annual), 1975-1978 (Box 29)
    - Rhodes, Frank, 1975-1976 (Box 29)
    - RN Studies, 1974-1979 (Box 29)
    - Schoen, Kathryn, 1977 (Box 29)
    - Smith, Allan F.
      - General, 1972-1974 (Box 29)
      - Salary Study, 1972/73 (Box 29)
        (includes background material from 1968)
    - Space, 1977/78 (Box 29)
    - Student Body Profile, 1973 (Box 29)
    - Student Nursing Council, 1974 (Box 29)
    - Student Nursing Crisis Service Report, 1974 (Box 29)
    - Students Graduated (Surveys), 1976-1977 (Box 29)
    - Study Skills, 1974 (Box 29)
    - Undergraduate Student Support Systems, 1977 (Box 30)
    - University Hospital Replacement Planning, 1976-1978 (Box 30)
- 1985-1990 Accessions, 1950-1990
  The records of the 1985-1988 Accessions subgroup primarily document the tenure of Dean Rhetaugh Dumas, but also include some materials from the days of Carolyne K. Davis. The records of this subgroup consist of Committee Records, Faculty Records, and Topical Files. These materials are arranged in a manner similar to the arrangement scheme used for the first two subgroups.
  - Committees Records, 1977-1989
    The Committee Records comprise 8 folders of materials arranged alphabetically by committee. The Space Needs (Emergency Committee) series contains materials that are especially enlightening on the physical plant requirements for modern nursing education.
    - Appointments, Promotion, and Tenure, 1982-1984 (Box 30)
    - Centennial Celebration Planning Committee, 1988 (Box 30)
    - Computer Assisted Learning Task Force, 1990 (Box 30)
    - Continuing Education Task Force, 1982-1984 (Box 30)
    - Executive Committee (Summary Notes)
      [see also Boxes 3 and 22]
      - 1979-1980 (Box 30)
      - 1981 (Box 30)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 30)
      - 1984-1985 (Box 30)
    - Facility Naming Committee, 1982-1983 (Box 30)
    - Faculty Development Committee, 1977-1985
      - 1977-1979 (Box 30)
      - 1984-1985 (Box 30)
    - Human Subjects Review Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 30)
    - Information Technology Committee, 1987-1989 (Box 30)
    - Nursing Faculty Salaries Task Force, 1983 (Box 30)
    - Quality Assurance (QA) Committee
      - Minutes, 1984-1986 (Box 30)
      - Nursing Research QA/Agenda, 1984 (Box 30)
      - JCAH (Joint Commission on Accreditation of Hospitals), 1984-1986 (Box 30)
      - Research/Dr. Ashcraft/Medical Nursing, 1984-1986 (Box 30)
      - PCE (Patient Care Evaluation) Reports, 1985 (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous/New Forms/Orientation, 1984-1986 (Box 30)
    - Space Needs Committee (Emergency), 1976-1977
      (see also Box 24)
      - General and Final Report, 1976-1977 (Box 30)
      - Equipment, 1976-1977 (Box 30)
      - Floor Plans, 1976-1977 (Box 30)
      - Minutes and Transcripts, 1977 (Box 30)
    - Space Planning Committee, 1984-1985 (Box 30)
  - Faculty Records, 1974-1990
    The Faculty Records include directories, meeting minutes, and surveys of research. The most interesting of these are the meeting minutes which provide detailed insights into the functioning of the school from 1974 to 1990.
    - Graduate Faculty Meetings, 1986-1990 (Box 31)
    - Meeting Minutes
      (see also Boxes 6, 7, and 25)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 31)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 31)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 31)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 31)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 31)
      - 1979-1980 (Box 31)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 31)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 31)
      - 1982-1983 (Box 31)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 31)
      - 1984-1985 (Box 31)
      - 1985-1986, 2 folders (Box 31)
      - 1986-1987, 2 folders (Box 31)
      - 1987-1988 (Box 31)
      - 1988-1989 (Box 31)
      - 1989-1990 (Box 31)
      - 1990 (Box 31)
    - Undergraduate Coordinators, 1985-1988; 2 folders (Box 32)
    - Undergraduate Faculty Meetings, 1987-1988 (Box 32)
  - Topical Files (primarily 1980s), 1950-1988
    The alphabetically arranged Topical Files document the 1980s, but there are historical materials dating from the 1950s and there is a construction proposal from 1976.
    - Awards
      - Distinguished Service Award, 1983 (Box 32)
      - Ella McNeil Award, 1983-1987 (Box 32)
      - Emilie Gleason Sargent, 1964-1985 (Box 32)
    - Center for Nursing Research, 1987-1988 (Box 32)
    - Clinical Nursing Specialist, 1970-1974 (Box 32)
    - Construction Proposal, 1976 (Box 32)
      [see also Boxes 24 and 30 "Space Needs/Building"]
    - History (by Patricia Butler), 1950-1953 (Box 32)
      (includes 298th General Hospital Photo)
    - McCain, Faye, Retirement, 1979-1980 (Box 32)
    - Nursing History Society, 1983-1986 (Box 32)
    - Patient Classification Indicator Definitions, 1984 (Box 32)
    - Reed Report, 1983 (Box 32)
    - Research Symposium Attendance Register, 1976-1988 (Box 32)
    - Review Report, 1980 (Box 32)
    - Strategic Plan, 1988 (Box 32)
    - Student Journal and Project (N476), 1985 (Box 32)
    - Surgical Nursing Standardized Nursing Care Plan/Patient Education Committee Orientation Booklet, 1983 (Box 32)
    - Syllabi, 1975-1985; 2 folders (Box 32)
- Photographs, 1900-1976
  The Photographs of the School of Nursing have been pulled together to stand as a distinct, processor-created subgroup. The photographs span the years from 1900 to the mid-1970s and are primarily class portraits.
  [see also outsize folder (UBI/mum/C261)]
  - Class Photos
    - Class of 1900 (Box 32)
      (including Fantine Pemberton)
    - Class of 1918 (Box 32)
    - Class of1 956 (Box 32)
    - Class of 1957 (Box 32)
    - Class of 1958 (Box 32)
    - Class of 1959 (Box 32)
    - Class of 1960 (Box 32)
    - Class of 1961 (Box 32)
    - Class of 1962 (Box 32)
    - Class of 1963 (Box 32)
    - Class of 1975 (Folder 1)
      (UBImum/C26)
    - Class of 1976 (Folder 1)
    - Class of 2009 (Folder 1)
      (UBImul/C26)
    - Dean Carolyn Davis, 2002 (Folder 1)
  - Topical Photos
    - Alumnae (Box 32)
    - Caps-History (Box 32)
    - Hospitals and Other Buildings (Box 32)
      (see also outsize folder UBI/mum/C261)
    - Junior-Senior Banquet (Box 32)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 1)
    - Staff and Students (Box 32)
- Mary Ann Swain, Research Area Chair, 1965-1986
  The subgroup Mary Ann Swain, Research Area Chairperson, accessioned in 1994, constitute an enhancement of the collection's coverage of research within the School of Nursing. Professor Swain joined the Nursing faculty in 1970, becoming Chairperson of the Research Area of the school in 1977. She was instrumental in the creation of doctoral programs at the School of Nursing and, consequently, this accession also strengthens the collection's coverage of graduate education in Nursing at the University of Michigan.
  - Topical File
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Curriculum, 1973-1974 (Box 33)
    - Area Chairpersons
      (see also Box 26 and Box 49)
      - 1978-1980 (Box 33)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 33)
    - Bylaws of the University of Michigan School of Nursing, Amended, 1979 (Box 33)
    - Center for Nursing Research, 1982-1984 (Box 33)
      (see also Box 32)
    - Correspondence, 1974-1985
      - Dumas, Rhetaugh, 1981-1983 (Box 33)
      - Lohr, Mary, 1976-1978 (Box 33)
      - Miscellaneous, 1974-1985 (Box 33)
    - Cost Analysis Task Force, 1979-1980 (Box 33)
    - Dismissal of Nursing Student and Subsequent Reaction of Campus Black Community, 1975 (Box 35)
    - Doctoral Program Faculty, 1979-1986
      - 1979-1980 (Box 34)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 34)
      - 1983-1984 (Box 34)
      - 1985-1986 (Box 34)
    - Executive Committee, Psychiatric Nursing Faculty Revolt, 1977 (Box 35)
    - Graduate Advisory Council, 1977-1980 (Box 34)
    - Graduate Curriculum Committee, 1975-1982
      - 1975-1978 (Box 34)
      - 1979-1982 (Box 34)
    - Graduate Faculty, 1973-1975 (Box 34)
    - Graduate Nursing Programs, Need Study, [1974 ?] (Box 34)
    - Graduate Study, Alternative Model, 1984 (Box 34)
    - Graduate Study Committee, 1973-1975 (Box 34)
    - Guidelines and Procedure for Use of Human Subjects in Research, 1970-1972 (Box 34)
      (see also Box 30)
    - Impact of Nursing on Cost Containment, [198?] (Box 34)
    - Promotions and Tenure Committee, 1979 (Box 34)
    - Proposal, Doctorate of Philosophy in Nursing, circa 1974 (Box 34)
    - Research Area Faculty, 1970-1982
      - 1970-1971 (Box 34)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 34)
      - 1975-1977 (Box 34)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 34)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 34)
      - 1982 (Box 34)
    - Research Design and Methodology, 1964-1974 (Box 34)
    - Research Facilitation Grant, Correspondence 1975-1976 and Final Report, 1980 (Box 34)
    - Research Review Committee, 1977-1980 (Box 34)
    - Search Committee (Joint), Assistant Dean of Graduate Studies and Director of the Center for Nursing Research, 1982-1983 (Box 34)
    - Steering Committee, Summer Report, 1974 (Box 34)
    - Task Force on Appointments, Promotion and Tenure, 1981-1982 (Box 34)
    - Technology Task Force, 1986 (Box 34)
- Dean Carolyne K. Davis and Successors, 1968-1980
  - Committee and Faculty Records, 1970-1980
    - Committee Records, 1970-1980
      - Executive Committee (Augmented)
        - 1977-1978, 6 folders (Box 35)
        - 1978-1979, 2 folders (Box 35)
      - Psychiatric Chairperson Search
        - 1979-1980 (Box 35)
    - Topical Files, 1968-1980
      - Appeals, Faculty, 1975; 2 folders (Box 35)
- Mary Ann Swain, Research Area Chair, 1965-1986
  - Topical Files
    - Dismissal of Nursing Student and Subsequent Reaction of Campus Black Community, 1975 (Box 35)
    - Executive Committee. Psychiatric Nursing Faculty Revolt, 1977 (Box 35)
- Dean Rhetaugh Dumas
  Following the pattern of previous subgroups, the records of Dean Rhetaugh Dumas, received in 2000, have been mainly divided into three series: Committee Records, Faculty Records, and Topical Files. A fourth series, Facilities Files, contains unprocessed files related to the design and construction of the School of Nursing's new facility in the old St. Joseph's Hospital. While the majority of the files in this subgroup are from Dean Dumas' tenure (1981-1994), small amounts of related material from the tenures of Deans Mary Lohr (1976-1980) and Ada Sue Hinshaw (1994-present), as well as some historical materials, are also included. Additional material on Dean Dumas' tenure can be found in the 1985-1988 accessions.
  - Committee Records (), 1974-1999; bulk 1981-1993
    The contents of the Committee Records, 1974-1999 (bulk 1981-1993) (9 linear feet), and Faculty Records, 1976-1996 (2 linear feet), are similar to those of previous accessions. The Committee Records series has been divided into two subseries, Standing Committees and Task Forces and Special Committees. Of particular note within the Committee Records are large runs of meeting minutes and supporting materials for the school's administrative council and executive committee. Also included are records of the search committees for various high profile positions within the school, including the inaugural selection of the Rhetaugh Graves Dumas Endowed Professorship in Nursing.
    - Standing Committees
      - Academic Admissions and Scholastic Standing
        - 1997-1999 (Box 73)
          [SR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2074 ]
        - 1996 (Box 73)
          [SR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2071 ]
        - 1995 (Box 73)
          [SR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2070 ]
        - 1993 (Box 36)
          [ER RESTRICTED until July 1, 2024 ]
        - 1992 (Box 36)
        - 1990-1991 (Box 36)
        - 1990-1992 (Box 36)
        - 1988-1989 (Box 36)
        - 1987 (Box 36)
        - 1986 (Box 36)
        - 1974-1976 (Box 36)
      - Administrative Council
        - 1996-1997 (ends with, October 1996 meeting) (Box 36)
        - 1995-1996, 2 folders (Box 36)
        - 1994-1995, 2 folders (Box 36)
        - 1993-1994, 2 folders (Box 36)
        - 1992-1993, 2 folders (Box 36)
        - 1991-1992, 4 folders (Box 37)
        - 1990-1991, 3 folders (Box 37)
        - 1989-1990, 3 folders (Box 37)
        - 1988-1989, 2 folders (Box 37)
        - 1987-1988, 2 folders (Box 37)
        - 1986-1987 (Box 37)
        - 1985-1986 (Box 37)
        - 1984-1985, 2 folders (Box 37)
        - 1983-1984 (Box 38)
      - Appointments, Promotion and Tenure
        - General, 1980-1994 (Box 73)
          [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2024 ]
        - Policies and Procedures, 1992 (Box 38)
      - Awards, 1985-1992 (Box 38)
      - Biomedical Research Review (defunct as of 9/94)
        - 1987-1993 (Box 38)
        - 1977-1986 (Box 38)
      - Bylaws (defunct as of 1985), 1975-1985; 2 folders (Box 38)
      - Curriculum
        - 1993-1996 (Box 38)
        - 1991-1992 (Box 38)
        - 1989-1990 (Box 38)
        - 1987-1988 (Box 38)
        - 1986, 2 folders (Box 38)
        - 1985 (Box 38)
      - Educational Resources, 1974-1981 (Box 38)
      - Elections
        - 1990-1993 (Box 38)
        - 1975-1989 (Box 38)
      - Executive Committee
        - 1995-1996, 3 folders (Box 39)
        - 1994-1995, 3 folders (Box 39)
        - 1993-1994
          - Agenda, Summary Minutes and Minutes (Box 39)
          - Supporting Materials, 3 folders (Box 39)
        - 1992-1993
          - Agenda, Summary Minutes and Minutes (Box 39)
          - Supporting Materials, 2 folders (Box 39)
        - 1991-1992
          - Agenda, Summary Minutes and Minutes (Box 39)
          - Supporting Materials, 2 folders (Box 39)
        - 1990-1991
          - Agenda, Summary Minutes and Minutes (Box 40)
          - Supporting Materials, 2 folders (Box 40)
        - 1989-1990
          - Agenda, Summary Minutes and Minutes (Box 40)
          - Supporting Materials, 2 folders (Box 40)
        - 1988-1989
          - Agenda, Summary Minutes and Minutes (Box 40)
          - Supporting Materials, 5 folders (Box 40)
        - 1987-1988
          - Agenda, Summary Minutes and Minutes (Box 41)
          - Supporting Materials, 6 folders (Box 41)
        - 1986-1987
          - Agenda, Summary Minutes and Minutes (Box 41)
          - Supporting Materials, 2 folders (Box 41)
        - 1985-1986
          - Agenda, Summary Minutes and Minutes (Box 41)
        - 1984-1985
          - Agenda, Summary Minutes and Minutes (Box 41)
        - 1983-1984
          - Agenda, Summary Minutes and Minutes (Box 41)
        - 1982-1983
          - Agenda, Summary Minutes and Minutes (Box 41)
        - 1981-1982, 2 folders (Box 41)
        - Miscellaneous
          - Annual Reports, 1983-1993 (Box 41)
          - Standing Rules, 1982-1995 (Box 41)
          - Standing Rules for Augmented Executive Committee, 1978-1981 (Box 41)
      - Faculty Development, 1975-1985; 3 folders (Box 42)
      - Graduate Admissions and Scholastic Standing, 1975-1985; 2 folders (Box 42)
      - Graduate Advisory Council, 1979-1982 (Box 42)
      - Graduate Curriculum
        - 1981-1985 (Box 42)
        - 1979-1980 (Box 42)
        - 1975-1978 (Box 42)
        - Annual Reports, 1978-1983 (Box 42)
      - Human Subjects Review, 1981-1984; 1985-1991 (Box 42)
      - Human Subjects Review/Research Ethics, 1975-1987 (Box 42)
      - International Affairs, 1988-1996 (Box 42)
      - Minority Affairs Advisory Committee (MAAC)
        - 1987-1992 (Box 42)
        - 1985-1986 (Box 42)
      - Multicultural Affairs Advisory Committee (MAAC), 1992-1994; 2 folders (Box 42)
      - Recruitment Advisory Committee, 1989-1991 (Box 42)
      - Research Ethics, 1975-1980 (Box 42)
      - Salary Equity Review, 1985-1994 (Box 42)
      - Undergraduate Admissions and Scholastic Standing (defunct as of 1986), 1978-1985 (Box 43)
      - Undergraduate Curriculum
        - 1985-1987 (Box 43)
        - 1984 (Box 43)
        - 1982-1983 (Box 43)
        - 1980-1981 (Box 43)
        - 1976-1980 (Box 43)
        - 1977-1979 (Box 43)
        - 1974-1976 (Box 43)
      - Miscellaneous
        - Annual Reports, 1981-1986 (Box 43)
        - Membership Lists, 1982-1990 (Box 43)
        - Standing Rules, 1980-1992 (Box 43)
        - Standing Rules Research, 1991-1992 (Box 43)
    - Task Forces and Special Committees
      - Ad Hoc Committee on Nursing Administration, 1987 (Box 43)
      - Admissions, Progression and Graduation, 1984 (Box 43)
      - Alcohol and Other Drugs, 1992 (Box 43)
      - Continuing Education, 1982-1983 (Box 43)
      - Distance Learning, 1996 (Box 43)
      - Faculty Development, 1992 (Box 43)
      - Faculty Governance, 1991-1992 (Box 43)
      - GradCare, 1992 (Box 43)
      - Information Technology, 1986-1988 (Box 43)
      - International Nursing, 1987-1988 (Box 43)
      - Mission, Philosophy and Objectives, 1990 (Box 43)
      - Nursing Faculty Salaries, 1982-1984 (Box 43)
      - Nursing Practice, 1983 (Box 43)
      - Partnership Task Force, 1993-1994 (Box 43)
      - Proposed Task Forces, 1989-1992 (Box 43)
      - Quality Improvement Team, 1997 (Box 43)
      - Recruitment and Marketing Visioning, 1992 (Box 43)
      - Revision of the Undergraduate Curriculum, 1986 (Box 43)
      - RN to Master's Option, 1985-1989 (Box 43)
      - Staff Development, 1992 (Box 43)
      - Streamlining Committee Work, 1992 (Box 43)
      - Undergraduate Curriculum Sequence Change (9-week calendar), 1985-1986 (Box 43)
      - Undergraduate Task Forces, 1983
        - Conceptual Framework, 1983 (Box 43)
        - Philosophy, Mission and Goals, 1983 (Box 43)
        - Review the Reports of the Undergraduate Program Consultants, 1983 (Box 43)
      - Work Environment, 1991-1992 (Box 43)
      - Search Committees
        - Associate Dean for Academic Affairs
          - General, 1992-1994; 5 folders (Box 44)
          - Candidates, 1993-1994 (Box 44)
        - Dean, 1993; 2 folders (Box 44)
        - Director of Division of Acute, Critical, and Long-Term Care Programs, 1990-1992; 2 folders (Box 44)
          [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2022 ]
        - Director of Undergraduate and Nontraditional Programs, 1994-1995; 2 folders (Box 44)
          [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2025 ]
        - Minority Affairs Director, 1991 (Box 44)
          [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2021 ]
        - Rhetaugh Graves Dumas Endowed Professorship in Nursing, 1995-1996; 5 folders (Box 44)
          [PR RESTRICTED until July 1, 2026 ]
  - Faculty Records, 1976-1996
    The Faculty Records are comprised of correspondence and policy documents related to faculty and agendas and minutes from school-wide faculty meetings (minutes of faculty meetings within specific academic areas are found in the Topical Files series). Dean Dumas' tenure was marked by a number of reorganizations and curricular changes, and the discussions and negotiations around these changes are reflected heavily in both the Committee Records and Faculty Records series.
    - Adjunct Appointment Requests, 1984-1994 (Box 45)
    - Administrative Reviews
      - Assistant Dean for Student Affairs, 1988-1989 (Box 45)
      - Assistant Dean for Undergraduate Studies, 1989 (Box 45)
      - Associate Dean for Administration, 1990 (Box 45)
      - Associate Dean for Graduate Studies, 1990 (Box 45)
      - Associate Dean for Graduate Studies, 1987 (Box 45)
      - Chair, Parent-Child Nursing, 1990 (Box 45)
    - Assistant Professors and Tenure, 1987 (Box 45)
    - Clinical Faculty Appointments, 1983 (Box 45)
    - Division of Health and Risk Reduction Programs, 1994-1996 (Box 45)
    - Doctoral Program, 1980-1983; 2 folders (Box 45)
    - Doctorally-Prepared Faculty, 1978-1992 (Box 45)
    - Doctorally-Prepared Faculty Research Interests, 1978-1979 (Box 45)
    - Faculty Climate Surveys, 1993 (Box 45)
    - Faculty Evaluation Procedures, 1985-1988 (Box 45)
    - Faculty Grievance Procedure, 1977-1985 (Box 45)
    - Faculty Handbooks, 1976-1982 (Box 45)
    - Faculty Meetings
      - 1995-1996, 3 folders (Box 45)
      - 1994-1995, 3 folders (Box 45)
      - 1993-1994, 3 folders (Box 45)
      - 1992-1993, 3 folders (Box 46)
      - 1991-1992, 2 folders (Box 46)
      - 1990-1991, 2 folders (Box 46)
      - Annual Reports, 1990-1994 (Box 46)
    - Faculty Practice, 1984-1994 (Box 46)
    - Faculty Research Symposium, 1984-1986 (Box 46)
    - Faculty Salaries-Average, 1983-1987 (Box 46)
    - Governing Faculty, 1979-1994 (Box 46)
    - Interim Review Policy, 1988-1989 (Box 46)
    - Joint Practice, 1985 (Box 46)
    - Junior Faculty Meeting, 1986 (Box 46)
    - Lecturer Appointments, 1984-1989 (Box 46)
    - Representation on Outside Committees, 1980-1991; 3 folders (Box 46)
    - Sabbatical Requests, 1987-1994 (Box 46)
    - Salaries, 1990-1992 (Box 46)
    - Survey of Non-Teaching Activities, 1981 (Box 46)
    - Tenure Track Faculty Qualifications, 1986 (Box 46)
    - Workload, 1978-1991 (Box 46)
  - Topical Files (), 1961-1999; bulk 1981-1993
    The Topical Files series, 1961-1999 (bulk 1981-1993) (22 linear feet), contains correspondence, charts, speeches and reports related to the school's activities and growth during this time period. Of particular note are the collected annual reports for the different academic areas and administrative offices of the school; the self-study reports prepared for the school's National League for Nursing reaccreditation in 1977, 1985, and 1993; information on the creation of the Nurse-Midwifery Program and the redesign of the Nursing Administration and Psychiatric Mental Health Nursing programs; and materials on the establishment of the school's Office of Minority Affairs (later renamed the Office of Multicultural Affairs). A small run of syllabi and other materials for School of Nursing courses is also included.
    Also included in the series are speeches Dean Dumas gave at various events, including School of Nursing orientations and convocations, university seminars, and nursing conferences. These speeches, in particular the dean's State of the School addresses, often comment on changes in the school and point to its future direction. The series also contains information on the dean's activities outside the university, including participation in nursing and other health-related associations, political advocacy, consulting, and research.
    - Academic Planning and Analysis, Office of-Memorandum of Understanding, 1977 (Box 47)
    - Academic Year Review, 1992-1993 (Box 47)
    - Academic Women's Caucus, 1987 (Box 47)
    - Accomplishments and Goals, 1977-1990 (Box 47)
    - Activity Budgeting, 1988 (Box 47)
    - Administration, Associate Dean for, 1989-1990 (Box 47)
    - Administrative Offices Function List, 1987-1988 (Box 47)
    - Administrative Support Procedures, 1986-1988 (Box 47)
    - Admissions-"Legacies,", 1991 (Box 47)
    - Advance Magazine, 1989-1994 (Box 47)
    - Advances in Psychiatric Mental Health Nursing, 1981-1983 (Box 47)
    - Advancing Career Opportunities for Registered Nurses (ACORN), 1989 (Box 47)